okay I'm about done - okay good
when the IceMen was discovered in the
austrian alps yet two types of mushrooms
yeah this mushroom ha Madhu which is the
firestarter mushroom that enabled humans
to migrate into colder environments the
Woodcock is called the fire starter or
tinder conk because he put embers of
fire in it and carry fire over distances
and if your clan needed to have fire to
survive and we in Europe we discovered
winter unusual but if you couldn't have
fire than your clan would die so the
fire keeper the tribe was incredibly
important to human survival and the
knowledge of keeping fire alive was
resident in the knowledge of polypore
mushrooms especially Amadou which is
extremely flammable my hat by the way
it's extremely flammable you can use the
fibers and the mycelium to stop fires
but he can use the to carry fires right
so it's you know the analogy could be
just like you know a piece of wood
versus paper you know or whatever so the
more surface area the more flammable the
material is so Amadou is one you know
they had he also had the another birch
polypore called picked a porous betcha
linus and the bootstrap mushroom this is
the only mushroom that I know that will
sharpen steel it's a relatively soft
mushroom but when it's in a ball form
you can cut it dry it a little bit in
the Sun it gets leathery and it's
actually called the bootstrap mushroom
because the sharpens steel I mean how
many mushrooms do you know sharp misdeal
this is the and we know about the fact
that this sharpest steel from the common
name and translated translated from the
ancient German so I mean if this
mushroom was not called the bootstrap
mushroom I bet you not too many this
knowledge would not have survived
because it linguistically it is survived
by Garak on that when I mentioned before
is called the elixir iam had long and
vitam 2,000 years ago the elixir of long
life and our research now as ironic two
thousand years after this mushroom was
discovered to be medicinal we
just looking at it for us you know new
pharmacological activities against
viruses and bacteria how dumb are 2,000
years to get around to the subject that
our ancestors discovered so how many
other species are there that we haven't
begun to discover so my hope is that
there's going to be a mycelial
revolution a revolution in the sciences
using fungi and one of the my biggest
the biggest one of the most focused
points that I can make is at the
University of Washington the Department
of astrobiology is better funded than
the Department of mycology
now I'd like astrobiology I think there
are organisms in outer space probably
are don't have any yet but we know in
the field and on this planet we have one
the 2 million species of fungi less than
10% of which have been identified it
seems to me that we have Mis prioritized
we've romanticized the concept of
organisms being out of space while
ignoring in our very home in our
backyard the ecosystems are collapsing
all around us due to our ignorance of
these fungal entities that are present
within us around us thank you very much
thank you